<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Balint Pekker | bpekker.dev]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Drupal related blog Written by Balint Pekker, a software engineer being really good at turning caffeine into code.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:57:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Drupal Prep Manual: Recipes!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Does the process of configuring modules and setting up content types manually from scratch sound all too familiar? Have you ever wished for a secret ingredient to simplify your Drupal development process? That's exactly what recipes bring to the table: a structured approach to site building that saves you precious hours of trial and error. After all, in the world of development, time equals money.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/drupal-recipes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/drupal-recipes/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 21:38:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[To Patch or Not To Patch]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is an ongoing debate among developers regarding the use of patches versus pull requests for contributions. Since its migration to GitLab in 2018, Drupal has undergone significant changes. As of July 2024, the removal of Drupal CI and automated patch testing could potentially change the way contributions are made.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/to-patch-or-not-to-patch/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/to-patch-or-not-to-patch/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 23:35:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Access Policy API]]></title><description><![CDATA[Drupal's robust architecture for role-based access control is highly effective, yet it does come with some limitations. Although several contributed modules such as Content Access, Field Permissions, Permissions by Term, or Flexible Permissions exist to address these limitations, from 10.3 we can utilize the built-in functionality of Drupal core to achieve the same outcome.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/access-policy-api/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/access-policy-api/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:34:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Attributes In Drupal]]></title><description><![CDATA[Drupal 10.2 is out, with an easier content management by improving user experience, and with some performance improvements in caching and HTTP responses. It is also compatible with PHP 8.3, and it started using PHP attributes.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/attributes-in-drupal/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/attributes-in-drupal/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 13:01:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Single Directory Components]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Drupal frontend development has long been intricate and demanding, however Drupal 10 introduces a game-changer — Single Directory Components (SDC).]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/single-directory-components/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/single-directory-components/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 18:12:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Journey So Far]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my initial post sharing my journey in web development so far — a journey that commenced during my college days and ultimately steered me towards becoming a passionate Drupal enthusiast.]]></description><link>https://bpekker.dev/the-journey/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bpekker.dev/the-journey/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 01:01:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>